Impossible. Impossible.
Nothing is impossible.
Come on, Mouse.
Dig!
Mouse, come on.
-Jehan.
-Yes, sir.
Get the next three.
Two more.
- Over there.
- Hurry up!
-Move!
- Take two.
- I want Phillipe Gaston.
-This is the cell, sir.
Wrong cell. I want Phillipe Gaston,
the one they call the Mouse.
The Mouse? Mouse.
The Mouse, he left our house.
No Mouse today. He's run away.
To ease the pain, he's down the drain!
-Where is he?
-I already told you, gentle lord.
Hang him. Search every sewer, every drain.
Find him, or Captain Marquet
will hang you in his place.
You can't hang me!
Impossible. Nobody could escape
through there.
It's not unlike escaping Mother's womb.
God, what a memory.
Out of the way!
Lord, I will never pick another pocket again
as long as I live, I swear it.
But here's the problem.
If you don't let me live,
how can I prove my good faith to you?
If you've heard me,
this ledge will remain steady as a rock,
and that thing coming at me
won't be what I think it is.
If it is, there's no hard feelings,
of course, but I'd be very disappointed.
I don't believe it.
I believe it.
I'm coming. I'm coming!
It's Phillipe, Lord.
Phillipe.
You won't regret this, Lord.
I'm a wonderful person.
Boy.
Hello. What are you doing down there?
Get away! Get away, get away, get away!
Come back. Come back!
There's disturbing news, Your Grace.
One of the prisoners has escaped.
No one ever escapes
from the dungeons of Aquila, Marquet.
The people of this city accept
that as a historical fact.
-The responsibility is mine.
-Yes.
It would be a miracle if he manages
to get through the sewage system.
I believe in miracles, Marquet.
It's part of my job.
At any rate, Your Grace,
it is only one insignificant, petty thief.
Great storms announce themselves
with a simple breeze, Captain.
And a single random spark
can ignite the fires of rebellion.
If he is out there, Your Grace,
I shall find him.
Yes.
Take 10 men towards Chenet!
We ride north to Gavroche!
The name of the man
who finds Phillipe Gaston
will be brought to the personal attention
of the Bishop,
as will the body of the man
who lets him get away!
Open the gates!
I know I promised, Lord. Never again.
But I also know that you know
what a weak-willed person I am.
Come on, Mouse. Keep going.
Not much farther.
About 350 miles. That's all.
A nice, hot piece of cabbage,
like my dear, old mother used to cook.
Wolf. Wolf.
Please, no wolf.
A joint of lamb.
Where the hell am I?
Hot lamb. Hot lamb. A little sauce on it.
Maybe some of that green stuff
little Bertram used to put on it.
-Hello.
-Look up there.
He's taking Daddy's shoes.
You've got it, little darlings.
Innkeeper.
-A drink of your most expensive.
-Yeah, yeah. Show me your money.
Copper, my friend.
And the same for anyone
who will join me in a toast.
Let's hear your toast.
We drink to a special man, my friend.
Someone who has been inside
the dungeons of Aquila
and lived to tell the tale.
Then you drink to me, little man.
I've seen those dungeons.
A blacksmith, perhaps?
A carpenter? A stonecutter, even?
But a prisoner from inside Aquila?
I didn't say I was a prisoner.
If you'd stuck to the woods,
you may have stood a chance, Gaston.
You're right.
Get him.
Move! Move!
Get out of the way.
You, I said, out!
I'm so terribly sorry.
Kill him.
May God have mercy on my soul!
You, out.
One of my men told me you returned.
I wanted to cut his throat for lying,
'cause I knew you weren't that stupid.
-Captain Navarre.
-Francesco.
Captain?
Navarre!
I won't hurt you. I'm a wonderful person.
After him!
Sweet ponies. Gentle... Come here.
You filthy strumpets!
No. No, no, no, no.
No, no, no, no.
No!
Must be somebody's home. There's smoke.
Are you sure you don't want to ride on, sir?
There's still plenty of light.
Stop your chattering.
We'll spend the night here.
Give me the ax. The ax.
Good afternoon, sir. My lady.
My comrade-in-arms and I need lodging
for the night.
No. No place for you here.
We'll pay for it, of course.
We are not above compassion
for those in misery.
You may sleep down there, in the barn.
Thank you.
Sir? Sir, are you there?
If there's nothing else I can do,
I think I'll turn in.
-You can take care of my horse.
-All right.
And sleep with one eye open.
And don't disturb me.
I'm liable to take your head off
before I know it's you.
All right. Come on, old girl.
Come on.
Stubborn little lady. What's her name?
His name is Goliath.
His name? Pretty name.
Go with him, boy.
He didn't mean to hurt your feelings.
Come on.
Goliath, before we get to know
each other better,
I feel I should tell you a story
about a teeny, little man named David.
One day.
"Comrade-in-arms."
Slave's more like it.
See to the fire, feed the animals,
gather the wood.
Look at me, Lord.
I was better off in the dungeons of Aquila.
My cellmate was insane and a murderer,
but he respected me.
He's a strange one, Navarre.
Why did he save my life?
He wants something from me.
I can see it in his eyes.
Well, whatever it is, I'm not going to do it.
I'm still a young man, you know.
I've got prospects!
I'm off to find my golden future, Captain.
So, goodbye and good...
Hello?
Who do you think is out there?
You'd better draw your sword, Pierre.
Ah! Louis, you brought your crossbow.
We'll all go back to the barn now, all right?
All right.
Show no mercy, Pierre!
We're not interested in prisoners.
Hold your ground, Louis.
I'll run ahead and get some help.
Captain! Sir! Captain!
Sir! Sir! Sir!
Wolf! Wolf! Wolf!
Sir! Sir!
Wolf! Wolf!
Wolf. Wolf.
Wolf! Wolf! Wolf!
Shh...
Don't go out there! Don't go out there!
There's a wolf, a big wolf.
The biggest wolf you've ever seen,
and a dead man.
I know.
Miss! Please!
Maybe I'm dreaming.
But my eyes are open,
which means maybe I'm awake
dreaming I'm asleep.
Or, more likely,
maybe I'm asleep, dreaming that I'm awake
wondering if I'm dreaming.
You are dreaming.
I have not seen what I have just seen.
I do not believe what I believe, Lord.
These are magical, unexplainable matters,
and I beg you
not to make me a part of them.
We'll stop now.
Not a great day for traveling.
Come on, old girl.
Come on... I mean, boy. Goliath.
Come on, Goliath.
Come on. It's cold out here. Come on!
I could do with some rest myself,
after last night's goings-on.
The wolf would have killed me.
It was horrible.
But he tore the farmer's throat out
and left me alone.
And there was more.
There was a woman,
like fine porcelain with deep blue eyes.
Almost like a bird's.
And her voice,
the dulcet tones of an angel.
She spoke? What did she say?
I asked her if I was dreaming.
She said I was.
Hmm.
I'm not insane. You must believe me
when I tell you these things.
No, I believe you. I believe in dreams.
I see.
This lady, did she perhaps have a name?
Not that she mentioned. Why?
Well, she might wander into my dreams.
Wouldn't it be nice
if I could call her by name
and pretend we'd met before?
I've waited a long time for such a lady.
Now, get some sleep.
The bird will alert us if anyone comes.
I've got to be out of my mind.
Out of my mind.
Open the gate!
Have you found the criminal,
Gaston?
He is not in my custody at this time.
Then why do you invade my garden,
unwashed, unshaved?
Do you think to find him here?
Navarre has returned.
Walk with me.
The criminal, Gaston, travels with him.
My men are combing the woods.
And the hawk?
-Your Grace?
-There must be a hawk.
A spirited hawk.
This hawk is not to be harmed.
Is that understood?
You see, the day she dies, a new captain
of the guard will preside at your execution.
We live in difficult times, Marquet.
This famine has prevented the people
from paying their proper tribute
to the Church.
I raise their taxes only to be told that
there is nothing left for me to tax. Imagine.
But last night,
the Lord Almighty visited me in my sleep.
He told me
that Satan's messenger
is traveling amongst us. And that his name
is Etienne of Navarre.
Go.
To break faith with me
is to break faith with Him.
-Get me Cezar.
-Yes, Your Grace.
This sword has been in my family
for five generations.
It has never known defeat, until now.
This jewel represents my family name.
This one is our alliance
with the Holy Church in Rome.
This one was my father's,
from the Crusades.
And this...
-Sir, you don't think I took that one?
-No.
This is mine to fill.
Each generation is called upon
to follow its own quest.
And what is your quest?
I must kill a man.
Tell me,
does this walking corpse have a name?
His Grace, the Bishop of Aquila.
The Bishop. I see.
Well... Well, then you have much to do.
And I've already been enough of a burden
to you.
I do hope our paths cross again one day.
I need you to guide me into the city.
Not for the life of my mother,
even if I knew who she was.
You're the only one
who has ever escaped from there.
It was chance, pure chance.
A miracle. Once in a lifetime.
I fell down a hole, and followed my nose.
I have waited almost two years
for a sign from God.
So when I heard
the warning bells of Aquila,
I knew the moment
of my destiny had come.
You will be my guiding angel.
Me?
Sir, the truth is I talk to God all the time.
And, no offense,
but he never mentioned you.
No?
There are strange forces at work
in your life.
Magical ones that surround you.
I don't understand them,
but they frighten me.
You have given me my life.
The truth is, I can never repay you.
I have no honor. I never will have.
I don't think that you would kill me
for being what I am.
But better that, than to return to Aquila.
I'll gather some wood for the fire.
-Got you.
- Miss?
My lady? Up here.
Damn.
You remember me?
What are you doing up there?
What am I doing? Yes, you might ask that.
The Bishop's guards.
A dozen of them. We had a terrible fight.
-Why didn't they kill you?
-Why didn't they?
That's a good question.
I asked them that myself.
-And?
-"And?"
And what did they say?
They said that they preferred
to leave that honor to the Bishop.
Oh.
They're coming back.
-They are, are they?
-Please, my lady.
A giant owl examined me quite closely,
not one minute ago.
Please?
Please.
You're very kind.
Listen.
Thank you very much, my lady.
Tell the captain he ties a wicked knot.
He's going to kill me.
Good morning.
Let's go find Phillipe.
Well, well.
A long way from the sewers, little rat.
This time the drinks are on me.
-Where's Navarre?
-Navarre? Navarre?
Yes, yes. Big man, black horse?
Uh... I saw him riding south, toward Aquila.
Then, we ride north, sir.
It's not polite to assume somebody is a liar
when you've only just met them.
And yet, you knew we would.
We ride south, toward Aquila.
-I told the truth, Lord.
-Move.
How can I learn any moral lessons
if you keep confusing me like this?
Hawk!
No.
Easy. You'll be all right.
Get me a piece of cloth from my saddlebag.
Easy. Don't be afraid. It's all right.
It's all right.
Thanks.
You'll be all right. You'll be fine.
You'll live.
Take her. Find help.
-Me, sir?
-You're the only one I have.
-But, sir, the poor thing is done for.
-Don't you say that!
Follow that road,
you'll find a ruined castle.
There's a monk named Imperius.
Give him the hawk.
He will know what to do.
-Sir, I don't think you understand...
-Get on my horse.
You're the only who can ride him.
You will do as I tell you.
Get on my horse, now!
Careful.
And know this,
if you fail,
I will follow you the length of my days.
And I will find you.
Go. Run.
Go!
There it is, see? The castle.
We'll be there soon.
Well. Well, that's gratitude for you.
All right, then.
Let this Imperius fellow watch you die.
I've got my own life to live after.
Please.
Hello!
Hello, up there!
For pity's sake, hello!
Hello, hello!
What do you want down there?
I was told to bring you this bird.
It's been wounded.
Good shot!
Bring it in, we'll dine together.
We can't eat this bird!
Why not? God, is it Lent again already?
This is no ordinary hawk, Father.
It belongs to a man named Navarre.
Mother of God.
Bring her in! Bring her in! Quickly!
Stay.
Good bird.
Up here, boy. Hurry!
Hurry!
Oh...
Here. Up here.
This way.
Now, careful.
Walk on the left side. On the left.
There.
Gently.
Now, leave us.
-Can I help?
-Go out, boy.
Don't be frightened.
Navarre was right.
I know what to do.
We must wait a little.
Now then, where is that...
There we are.
Now then, what am I going to need?
Celeriac, rosemary, thyme.
Did I light the fire?
It's late. Thyme, I need thyme.
Now, I need a root. There! That's it.
Navarre. Is he...
He's fine.
He's just fine, my lady.
There was a terrible battle.
Navarre fought like a lion.
The hawk...
The hawk was struck.
You know that, don't you?
Yes.
Are you flesh?
Or are you spirit?
I am sorrow.
How...
Get out.
Out, out.
This time, stay out!
Ready?
Forgive me, Your Grace. Cezar has arrived.
It's him, isn't it?
-The wolf. Somehow, it's him.
-Drink. Forget.
An hour ago you were drunk,
and you remembered.
-What do they call you, boy?
-Phillipe Gaston.
Uh-huh.
Her name is Isabeau d'Anjou.
Her father was the Comte d'Anjou,
an intemperate fellow.
He died slaughtering Saracens in Antioch.
She came to live with a cousin,
I think it was, in Aquila.
I shall never forget the first time
I saw her. It was like looking at...
The face of love.
You, too.
Well, I suppose we were all in love with her
in different ways.
Even His Grace, the Bishop,
could think of nothing else.
The Bishop loved her?
As near as that evil man could come to it.
His passion was a sort of madness.
He was a man possessed.
But Isabeau sensed his wickedness,
and she shrank from him.
She sent back all his letters unopened,
his poems unread.
Her heart was already lost, you see,
to the captain of the guard.
Etienne Navarre!
The Bishop knew nothing of their love.
But every day saw it grow stronger
and deeper and richer.
Until...
Until?
They were betrayed.
They shared the same confessor,
a weak and foolish priest.
And one day, in a drunken confession
to his superior, he committed a mortal sin.
He revealed the lovers' secret vows
to the Bishop.
The old fool didn't realize
what he had done at first,
nor the terrible revenge
the Bishop would take.
His Grace seemed to go mad.
He lost both his sanctity and his reason.
He swore that if he could not have her,
no man would.
So, Navarre and Isabeau fled from Aquila.
But the Bishop followed,
never more than an hour behind,
and more persistent than a hound.
An evil man, a powerful man,
hated and feared.
Rejected even by Rome herself.
He called upon the powers of darkness
for the means to damn the lovers.
In his fury and frustration,
he struck a dreadful bargain
with the evil one.
The dark powers of hell
spat up a terrible curse,
and you have seen it working.
By day, Isabeau is the beautiful bird
you brought to me.
And by night, as you have already guessed,
the voice of the wolf that we hear
is the cry of Navarre.
Poor, dumb creatures with no memory
of the half-life of their human existence.
Never touching in the flesh.
Only the anguish of a split second
at sunrise and sunset
when they can almost touch,
but not.
Always together. Eternally apart.
As long as the sun rises and sets,
as long as there is day and night.
And for as long as they both shall live.
You have stumbled onto a tragic story,
Phillipe Gaston.
And now, whether you like it or not,
you are lost in it, with the rest of us.
Useless.
All of them.
My traps are full.
I can't kill every wolf that lives.
Since the plague,
there are more wolves than men.
And there's a woman.
Your Grace?
A beautiful woman
with alabaster skin, and the eyes of a dove.
She travels by night, only by night.
Her sun is the moon.
And her name is
Isabeau.
Find her, and you find the wolf.
The wolf I want.
The wolf who
loves her.
A black wolf.
Isabeau.
Don't. Don't.
You might start bleeding again.
Tell me your name.
Most people call me Phillipe the Mouse.
You travel with him, don't you?
Yes.
"You must save this hawk," he said.
"For she is my life,
my last and best reason for living."
And then he said,
"One day we will know such happiness
as two people dream of, but never do."
He said that?
I swear it on my life.
-Does she know?
-What?
That you were the priest
that betrayed them?
God has declared an end to it, at last.
He has given me the knowledge
to undo what I have done.
After two years,
he has brought us back together again.
Make yourself clear, if you can.
I have found a way to break the curse
and a time for Navarre
to confront the Bishop
and to begin his own true life again.
He intends to confront the Bishop,
to kill him with the sword of his ancestors.
No, he mustn't do that. He can't.
If he kills the Bishop,
the curse can never be broken.
Go look after Isabeau, boy. Go, quickly.
Open up the door, in the name
of His Holiness, the Bishop of Aquila!
Be off with you!
This is a house of God, not a brothel!
I said open up, in the name of the Bishop!
I met the Bishop, you blasphemous lout!
And you look nothing like him.
-Break it in!
-Yes, sir.
Left side, left side, left side.
Come on.
My lady. My lady.
Come with me.
-What is it?
-Don't talk, come with me.
Sorry!
I am a monk, not an architect!
Move, imbecile!
In here, my lady.
This way, my chum.
Straight through the big main doors.
And don't forget...
Walk on the left side.
Careful. Hurry.
Go back! Go back! Back inside! Run!
I got you!
He's got me!
Get off, get off, get off!
Get off of me.
My boots!
-Phillipe, it's me they're after.
-Don't flatter yourself.
Hold me!
I'm slipping!
No!
You!
-Where's the woman?
-She flew away.
-Where is she?
-God's truth, she flew away!
You...
It always pays to tell the truth, Lord.
Thank you. I see that now.
I thought you might have been dead,
old man.
There were times
I wanted to kill you myself.
But I'm very grateful for this.
No, it is I who should be grateful
to have the chance to redeem myself,
and to save you and Isabeau,
because God has told me
how the curse may be broken.
You have betrayed us once. I warn you.
Three days hence, the Bishop will hear
the confession of the clergy
in the cathedral in Aquila.
All you have to do is confront him,
both of you, as man and woman,
in the flesh.
And the curse will be confounded, broken.
And both of you will be free!
-Impossible.
-As long as there is night and day, no.
But three days hence in Aquila,
there will be a day without a night
and a night without a day.
Go back inside, old man.
Go back to your drink.
You think I'm drunk?
I swear to you!
God has shown me!
He has forgiven me.
He hasn't forgiven you.
He's made you mad.
Sir. Sir.
It's all right, Father. Sir?
Sir.
How's your shoulder?
-I'm in your debt.
-Me, sir? No, no, not at all.
She wanted me to deliver a message,
to say she still has hope, faith in you.
-You are free to go.
-I know that, sir.
-Do as you like.
-Yes, sir.
Then you and Ladyhawke
will be going on to Aquila?
Ladyhawke?
Yes.
Well, it just so happens, I'm heading
in that general direction myself.
Really?
Then you better grab your things.
I'm leaving now.
Right.
Ladyhawke.
Imperius, I'm leaving with the captain.
Follow us.
But if the old man's right
about breaking the curse,
if you and Isabeau could face
the Bishop together, as man and woman...
You will not mention that again.
Not to me, not to her.
Understood?
Abraham,
will you get a move on?
Looks like a big one, Captain.
We're going to get soaked.
Find shelter.
Come here.
-The sun is going down.
-How can you tell?
After so many sunsets?
Take care of Ladyhawke.
Tell her I love her.
You hungry?
Do you understand me, Ladyhawke?
You know,
it's my favorite thing for dinner, hawk.
I've eaten thousands of them.
Used to kill one every night.
Serves me right
for getting involved in this nightmare.
Nightmare, daymare.
And then, "A night without day,
a day without night."
What's that supposed to mean?
Makes about as much sense
as the rest of it.
Uh-oh.
Sunset.
I'll wait outside.
Hold on for a minute.
I can't vouch for the fit.
Take your time, my lady.
Miss.
My lady?
I'm coming in.
Miss?
It's me, remember?
You?
Yeah.
Thank you.
-How is he?
-He's alive, like you.
He's full of hope, like you.
He left you in my charge.
He said, "Tell her we two speak as one,
"and she will follow your instructions
as my own."
Really?
-I...
-No, don't swear.
Good evening, Goliath.
He's taking us back to Aquila, isn't he?
Well, what do you instruct?
I instruct you to sit by a warm fire,
to drink a cup of sweet wine,
and to listen to bright music,
cheerfully played.
Perhaps, dance.
Shall we, my lady? Dance?
-Now?
-Practice.
Oh, my.
It has been a long time, Phillipe.
I'll take my cup of sweet wine now.
All right.
So, you intend to be my protector, as well?
I'm flattered.
Actually, the truth is,
he'll kill me if I lose it.
-You stole my dress?
-I wouldn't...
Isabeau. Isabeau.
Isabeau.
-Get inside.
-No!
Get inside!
If you lay one hand on her,
you'll find it on the ground,
next to your head!
-Now, ride on!
-Easy, little man, you're frightening me.
Are you deaf? Ride on!
Turn around, and you're dead!
What a terrible night.
Isabeau!
He'll kill me.
Show yourself, coward!
My beauty.
Navarre!
Black wolf.
Do get on, Abraham.
Go on, faster. It's going to snow soon.
Good morning.
-Good morning.
-You look a little pale.
-I got you something to eat.
What a night.
What happened?
Nothing I couldn't handle, Captain.
It's a good little hawk. Nice bird.
Go on now. Go to your master.
-Go on, Ladyhawke.
-Last night...
-Captain?
-Tell me about it.
What's to tell? Go on now.
Go on. Go, go, go!
We ran into a bit of trouble
on our way to an inn.
You took Isabeau to an inn?
First, we had to go to a stable.
Fly to your master, fly to the one you love.
-What did you do in a stable?
-We changed clothes.
-What?
-Not together, of course.
-You left her alone?
-No, never.
-So, you did change?
-No, no, no. No.
-Take her.
-Come here.
Take her, take her, take her.
She's the most wonderful woman
that ever lived.
And I can't say I haven't had my fantasies.
But the truth is,
all she did was talk about you.
Every moment you spend with her,
I envy you.
But you can tell me.
Tell me everything that she said.
And I warn you,
I will know if the words are hers.
She was sad at first.
She talked about the day you met,
and she cursed it.
But then I saw her remember
how happy you were together,
before the Bishop's curse,
and her eyes glowed.
No, she glowed.
She loves you more than life, Captain.
She's had to.
Do you know that hawks and wolves
mate for life?
Yeah.
The Bishop didn't even leave us that.
Not even that.
On your way to kill His Grace?
Why won't you listen to me?
In two days' time,
you can face the Bishop in the cathedral
with Isabeau by your side
and break the curse.
I will be in Aquila tomorrow.
And one way or another,
there will finally be an end to it.
One day, more or less.
-What could it matter?
- You, too?
I warned you.
-Stay here, then, with the old man.
-No. I'm going with you.
How will you get inside the cathedral
without me?
I will get in, without your help.
Thank you for trying, Phillipe,
and for standing up for the truth.
I should've known better.
Every happy moment in my life
has come from lying.
There you are, little Mouse.
Where is my knife?
-Isabeau?
-I just had it here.
Now, what have I done with it?
Isabeau, this may be
our last evening together.
-Why?
-I didn't want to tell you until I believed.
I mean, really believed.
Really believed what, Phillipe?
I think we can break the curse.
We have a plan.
-You and Navarre?
-No.
Must you keep thumping me
in the liver?
Imperius, this hole's not big enough
for the two of us.
Well, let's hope it's
big enough for the wolf.
Ow!
What are you doing?
When you kneel before the altar,
how do you get up again?
You sacrilegious young imp!
Go on, push. Blast you!
And more. Again!
And again! Up!
Up!
He's coming! He's coming!
-Phillipe!
-My lady, my lady,
we're just covering the trap.
All right. Hurry.
He's coming across the ice.
- Wait, my lady.
-Phillipe! Help me!
The ice, it will break!
Lie down! Lie down!
He can't get out!
Wait!
Wait, my lady!
God, Phillipe! I can't make it!
-Hurry!
- I'm coming.
Hurry, boy! We'll lose him!
Wait!
He's too heavy! He's too...
Phillipe... No! He's slipping! He's...
Hold him!
Stop! Be careful!
No!
Isabeau!
Isabeau, hold him up!
-No! Phillipe!
-Phillipe! No!
Phillipe!
No! No!
Push. Push.
It's all right.
Hold on.
Hold on, boy!
We must live, Father.
As human beings.
Our lives are in your hands now.
Tell me one thing,
where is my father's sword?
It's gone.
It fell through the ice last night,
crossing the river.
Damn you.
That sword was the last bit of honor
I possessed.
There is no mission of honor now.
The jewel that you wished to place
in your sword hilt
has become a symbol
of your meaningless death.
But there is a chance for life now.
A new life with her.
I needed that sword to kill the Bishop!
Navarre, listen to him!
-Damn you!
-Go ahead then.
Kill yourself! Kill her, too!
You never cared for her
as much as yourself anyway.
What is that?
That happened last night,
when he saved your life.
Forgive me.
I'll show you idiots how to cage a wolf.
Quickly!
Get out of the way there!
Remember, the cul-de-sac
is by the great north wall.
Right, right. Cul-de-sac, great north wall.
Come on. Come on.
We have come full circle, Lord.
I would like to think that there is
some higher meaning in all of this.
Certainly would reflect well on you.
Halt!
What have we here, little Father?
A surprise present,
my son, for His Grace, the Bishop,
from the people of my parish.
A fine pelt for his wall.
What have we here?
I've never had the pleasure
of killing a wolf before.
How strange.
That's exactly what the Bishop said.
I'm sure he will understand
your depriving him of that pleasure.
He's a very forgiving sort of a man.
Very well. Pass on.
Wisdom is beyond price, my son.
Be grateful that you have it.
-Your Grace?
-When I am ready.
It should be soon now.
Once the clouds break.
It's day, old man.
Like it was yesterday,
like it will be tomorrow.
Oh, no.
Damn.
-What's the matter?
-Rats.
Rats? Here?
Scandalous.
There's no time left.
The Mass will be over soon.
I cannot wait for you now.
If Phillipe has done his job,
I can kill the Bishop now or never.
No, Etienne,
this chance will never come again!
You're right.
If this service ends peacefully,
the cathedral bells begin to toll,
and you will know I have failed.
But Isabeau...
I
beg you, take her life.
Quick and painless.
I can't do that.
Yes, you can. I beg you.
The cruelty would be to damn her
to a half-life.
And that is not what she wants.
I couldn't do it.
Have you ever considered that
this is what God intended all along?
As the one who was your captain
and through God's grace will be once again,
I ask you to let me pass.
Captain Navarre,
I have my orders.
Damn it, open!
Come on.
Navarre!
Thank you, Lord.
Night without a day.
Day without a night.
Dear Lord, go with him. Be with him.
Imperius! Wait!
No!
You're dead.
Stop!
Imperius,
make it quick.
God, forgive me.
But kill me, Navarre,
and the curse will go on forever.
We must think of Isabeau.
Isabeau
is dead.
Damn you.
-Damn you to hell.
- Navarre!
Look at her.
Look at her!
Look at me.
Now,
look at us.
Look at us!
It's over. It's broken.
And no man shall...
Navarre!
Isabeau.
Oh, my God!
You cut your hair.
I love you.
Isabeau.
Navarre.
You two!
Come here.
May God's blessings
be with you both, from this day forward.
I bless the day
he brought you back to us, Father.
And you. And you.
The truest friend we could ever have.
Thank you.
I fully expect to meet you
at the Pearly Gates, little thief.
Don't you dare disappoint me.
I'll meet you there, Father.
Even if I have to pick the lock.
Isabeau!
I love you!